<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>
  <channel>
    <title>Meek.ly Blog</title>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:3000/blog/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <link>http://localhost:3000/blog</link>
    <description></description>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 00:15:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod> hourly </sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency> 1 </sy:updateFrequency>		
    <item>
      <title>New post</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3000/blog/how-to-hear-the-voice-of-the-lord-part-2/</link>
      <comments>http://localhost:3000/blog/how-to-hear-the-voice-of-the-lord-part-2/#respond</comments>      
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Dennis Jernigan]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 07:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[Devotional]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[Encouragement for Believers]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[The Voice of God]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:3000/blog/?p=1711</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p> &#8220;My sheep hear my voice, and I know them, and they follow me&#8230;&#8221; — John 10:27 KJV Last month I shared about the truth revealed in God’s Word that tells...</p>
        <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://localhost:3000/blog/how-to-hear-the-voice-of-the-lord-part-2/">How to Hear the Voice of the Lord (Part 2)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://localhost:3000/blog">Meek.ly Blog</a>.</p>
        ]]>
      </description>
      <content:encoded>
        <![CDATA[<blockquote>
        <div><span style="font-size: large;"> </span>&#8220;My sheep hear my voice, and I know them, and they follow me&#8230;&#8221; — <em><strong>John 10:27 KJV</strong></em></div>
        </blockquote>
        <div>
        <p><a href="http://localhost:3000/blog/how-to-hear-the-voice-of-the-lord-part-one/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Last month</em></a> I shared about the truth revealed in God’s Word that tells us we, as His sheep, can hear His voice and how I came to that realization. My journey took me from having my mind blown by the possibility of hearing God’s voice to a 12-year fast from other voices vying for my mind’s attention. God ultimately speaks through His Word, but we must remember we have a relationship with the living Word of God—Jesus Christ—and not with a book.</p>
        <p>The truth is that if you are a new creation in Christ, you are one of His sheep…and His sheep can hear His voice. One thing to remember is that God can speak to anyone He wants to—even unbelievers. My personal belief is that Father God is constantly speaking out His love to His lost sheep in a massive variety of ways. When I was lost, I did not have ears to hear because I had shut God out of my life. When I was born again and began to look back upon the events of my life that led me to repentance, I can see very clearly how often and how passionately God was speaking out to me to,</p>
        <blockquote>
        <h4>“Seek Him while He may be found.” — <em>Isaiah 55:6 NIV</em></h4>
        </blockquote>
        <p>My simple point is this: we can hear the voice of the Lord but we should not limit Him to any one means of ‘speaking’. What follows are various ways—according to the written Word of God—that God chooses to speak. What I am finding out as I grow older is that I should never put God in a box that says ‘He can only speak in this way or that’. The minute we put God in a box, that is all we get of Him. Let’s take God out of the boxes we have placed Him in and see <em>how creatively</em> He chooses to speak into our lives.</p>
        <p>&nbsp;</p>
        </div>
        <div>
        <h2>Forms of Communication</h2>
        <p>Just as we have many ways of speaking to one another on a human level, so, too, God has created many varied ways for us to speak to and hear from Him. Again, this is not meant to be an exhaustive study on hearing God&#8217;s voice. My main desire is to let you know really how simple communication with God can be—that we can hear His voice if we learn to listen. I also hope to stir up in you a desire to seek God in deeper and more creative ways. His presence is much more vast and magnificent than you or I have discovered to this point&#8230;and that is as it should be!</p>
        <p>Listed below are <em>many of the ways</em> I have personally used <em>to hear God&#8217;s voice</em>&#8230;to know His heart.</p>
        <h3>Prayer</h3>
        <p>What is prayer? According to the dictionary, prayer is simply communion with God. Communion is the sharing of thoughts and feelings. In other words, when we pray we are simply communicating with God our thoughts and feelings. Simply put, prayer is talking to God! One of my greatest joys in talking with God is that I do not have to wait until all is quiet and I am alone with Him. We can approach Him boldly anytime or anyplace for any reason&#8230;even in the midst of a worship time we are leading&#8230;or even in a crowded room&#8230;in a storm&#8230;or in a quiet moment alone.</p>
        <p>Prayer is simply talking to God. Of course, when talking with someone we must always remember to take time to listen for the other party&#8217;s response!<em> (Hebrews 4:16).</em> Also, remember that prayer can take on many varied forms: unknown tongues, groanings, wailing, tears, etc. Do not ever look down upon the various forms of prayer. God uses them all!<em> (See &#8220;Other People&#8221; in this same chapter.)</em></p>
        <h3>The Holy Spirit</h3>
        <p>The Holy Spirit is God&#8217;s Spirit on earth. Jesus said that once He had ascended into heaven that He would send a Comforter—the Holy Spirit—to be our guide in this life&#8230;to facilitate God&#8217;s presence on earth! Jesus promised to send Him to comfort, teach, and lead us <em>(John 14:16; John 14:26; John 15:26; John 16:7).</em> What we must realize is that He is real and that He is with us. He will not leave. He will not forsake us. If He is with us, we must simply believe and receive that truth by faith&#8230;and dive heart first into a communion with Him!</p>
        <h3>Visions</h3>
        <p>What is a vision? Something perceived by the spirit from the heart of God—a supernatural sight! God&#8217;s Word tells us that God often spoke to His people through visions. Remember Ezekiel and Daniel? What is so awesome about our relationship with God is that He has promised in His written Word to do the same thing for us! For me, visions come when I allow God to speak to my mind through the spiritual realm of His nature&#8230;to see my life from His point of view.</p>
        <blockquote>
        <h4>And it shall come to pass afterward, that I will pour out My spirit upon all flesh; and your sons and your daughters shall prophesy, your old men shall dream dreams, your young men shall see visions&#8230;&#8221; —<em> Joel 2:28 KJV</em></h4>
        </blockquote>
        <h3>Dreams</h3>
        <p>What is a dream or what does it mean to dream? To dream, for the believer, means to meet with God in our sleep! He did so for Joseph and for others in Scriptural history&#8230;and He has promised to do the same for us! One of my favorite things to do is to go to bed anticipating meeting with God in my sleep. Often He will give me great visions as I sleep, thus combining two forms of communication, visions and dreams! We should never limit God&#8217;s ability to speak to us as we sleep&#8230;and should never limit our ability to hear and receive from Him even in our sleep. After all, we are new creations! We are His children!</p>
        <blockquote>
        <h4>It is vain for you to rise up early, to retire late, to eat the bread of painful labors; For He gives to His beloved even in his sleep. — <em>Psalm 127:2 NASB</em></h4>
        </blockquote>
        <h3>Nature</h3>
        <p>What is nature? The material or physical world and all it contains. God spoke all of creation into existence. He put that creation in motion and gave it order. Through nature He has often spoken—loudly and clearly. He made it and it belongs to Him. He uses it as He wills <em>(Psalm 29:3-9).</em> If you don&#8217;t believe me just think about the children of Israel in bondage to Egypt. God needed to get Pharaoh&#8217;s attention&#8230;so He sent a ravaging hail storm, a plague of frogs, a pestilence of flies, and even turned the Nile River into blood. God uses nature&#8230;and still does today. <em>Are you listening?</em></p>
        <h3>Angels</h3>
        <p>Angels are supernatural beings, created by God to do His bidding and to deliver His messages. An angel, after all, was used to tell Mary she would be the earthly vessel God would use to bring His Son to this world. They are His personal messengers—and they are active even today. <em>Are you listening?</em> <em>(Matthew 28:5; Luke 1:13; Luke 1:18-19; Luke 1:28; Luke 1:30; Luke 1:34; Luke 1:35).</em></p>
        <h3>Circumstances</h3>
        <p>How many times have we asked, &#8220;Why did You allow this to happen, Lord?&#8221; Somehow, inherently, we seem to know God is a good God, yet we know that even in His goodness bad things happen. Why? Because of sin, pain and suffering came into this world. Because we are not forced to love Him—because He wants us to want Him—He gives us a choice in serving Him. When bad things happen to us, there are any number of reasons God has allowed them. The glory is that He can take anything that life throws our way and then use it to speak life into our hearts. Paul was shipwrecked for a reason <em>(Acts 27:41).</em> Jesus was crucified for a reason <em>(John 3:16).</em> God uses the circumstances of this life to build His life into us.</p>
        <blockquote>
        <h4>And we know that God causes all things to work together for good to those who love God, to those who are called according to His purpose. — <em>Romans 8:28 NASB</em></h4>
        </blockquote>
        <p>Even though I have never personally heard the audible voice of God, I know He still speaks—because He has not changed! He spoke audibly many times throughout Scripture <em>(Acts 9:3-6)</em>&#8230;and I believe He still desires to do so today<em>.</em> <em>Are you listening?</em></p>
        <h3>Still Small Voice</h3>
        <p>This one I have heard! When I listen for God&#8217;s voice—especially after asking a specific question—I wait for Him to speak to the center of my being—what I call the place of ‘knowing&#8217; in the center of who I am<em>.</em> The best way I can explain it is that sometimes ‘I just know&#8217;!</p>
        <h3>Other People</h3>
        <p>God often sent human messengers to speak for Him. Moses and Samuel are two that come readily to mind. In my own life I have had several such experiences. One I recall quite vividly involves the near-death of my wife, Melinda. She had just given birth to our twin boys nine weeks early. The very next day her liver began to hemorrhage&#8230;and we were told we faced a matter of life and death. I began to weep and asked God to help me because I could not pray&#8230;I could only cry (a form of prayer). He spoke in that ‘still small voice&#8217;, telling me that He would save the tears I cried. I did not understand&#8230;and wondered if I had really heard His voice.</p>
        <p>A few moments later, a nurse came to me telling me she had been called in for duty&#8230;and that God had sent her just for me and Melinda! She told me God had raised up many people to stand in the gap for us. As she was about to leave, she said she had one more thing from the Lord. She told me that He wanted me to know that He saved all my tears when I cried&#8230;and that He would use them as weapons of prayer to put back the enemy! God uses others. <em>Do we listen?</em></p>
        <h3>Combinations</h3>
        <p>I am sure, if we took the time, we would find many, many instances of God using one or more means of communication in conjunction with another. How many times have we experienced circumstances and heard God speak through them and then to confirm His message through His written Word or through another person or through nature, etc? He often used angels and dreams together to speak His heart and will to His children <em>(Matthew 1:20; Matthew 2:13; Matthew 2:19).</em></p>
        <p><em>Next month, I will share the final part in this series and discuss more practical applications of how to sharpen one’s ability to hear the voice of the Lord.</em></p>
        </div>
        <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://localhost:3000/blog/how-to-hear-the-voice-of-the-lord-part-2/">How to Hear the Voice of the Lord (Part 2)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://localhost:3000/blog">Meek.ly Blog</a>.</p>
        ]]>
      </content:encoded>            
      <wfw:commentRss>http://localhost:3000/blog/how-to-hear-the-voice-of-the-lord-part-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
      <slash:comments>0</slash:comments>      
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
